[nautical music]
[航海音乐]
*
[rope creaking]
[绳索嘎吱作响]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Oh, look at
that cloud, Gary.
- 哦，看
那朵云，加里。
It looks just like
a giraffe eating ice cream.
它看起来就像
一只长颈鹿在吃冰淇淋。
- [meows]
- You're right, Gary.
- [喵]
- 你是对的，加里。
All this cloud-watching...
所有这些云观看...
[stomach grumbles]
is making me hungry too.
[肚子咕咕叫]
也让我饿了。
Ooh!
Look at that big one, Gary.
哦！
看看那个大家伙，加里。
And getting bigger
and bigger
并且越来越大
更大
and bigger
and bigger and--ow!
更大
更大，而且——噢！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
- [meow]
- [喵]
[sniffing]
[嗅嗅]
- Hey, Gary.
That was a pretty heavy cloud.
- 嘿，加里。
那是一片相当厚重的云。
- [meows]
- You're right, Gary.
- [喵]
- 你是对的，加里。
It's not a cloud at all.
[grunts]
这根本不是云。
[咕哝]
Let's see what's inside.
让我们看看里面有什么。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Ooh, fortune cookies!
哦，幸运饼干！
Vague prophecies baked into
delicious bite-sized snacks.
模糊的预言被融入
美味的一口大小的小吃。
These cookies can
see the future, Gary,
这些cookies可以
看到未来，加里，
which means they knew we were
hungry even before we did.
这意味着他们知道我们
甚至在我们之前就饿了。
Let's eat!
Mmm!
我们吃饭吧！
嗯！
[both eating noisily]
【两人吃饭吵闹】
[reading]
[阅读]
[gasps]
Did you hear that, Gary?
[喘气]
你听到了吗，加里？
The fortune is true!
财运是真的！
Let's look at your future.
让我们看看你的未来。
"Happy trails
will follow you always."
“快乐的足迹
会永远跟随你。”
[gasps]
Your fortune came true too!
[喘气]
你的财运也成真了！
Cookies with fortunes
that actually come true?
带有财富的饼干
这真的实现了吗？
We have to share
these with everybody!
我们必须分享
这些和大家一起！
- No, SpongeBob,
we are not handing out
- 不，海绵宝宝，
我们不分发
anything free
with every purchase.
任何免费的东西
每次购买。
Even the smiles here
cost a nickel.
就连这里的笑容
花费五分钱。
- Aw! Why not, Mr. Krabs?
- [laughs]
- 噢！为什么不呢，蟹老板？
- [笑]
Because, SpongeBob,
fortune cookie fortunes
因为，海绵宝宝，
幸运饼干的命运
are always lame
and they never come true.
总是蹩脚
但它们从未实现。
- Oh, but that is where
you're wrong, Squidward.
- 哦，但那就是那里
你错了，章鱼哥。
These fortune cookies
are different.
这些幸运饼干
是不同的。
Try one.
尝试一个。
- No.
- Oo-oop!
- 不。
- 噢噢！
- Eh.
- 呃。
[chewing]
[咀嚼]
[sighs]
"You will be rewarded
[叹气]
“你将会得到回报
for your particular talents."
Right.
为了你的特殊才能。”
对。
- Excuse me,
Mr. Squidward Tentacles?
- 对不起，
章鱼哥先生的触手？
You have just won
你刚刚赢了
"The Most Miserable Cashier
In Bikini Bottom" contest.
《最惨的收银员》
在“比基尼泳裤”比赛中。
Here's your cash prize.
Ha ha!
这是你的现金奖励。
哈哈！
[tooooot]
[太呜呜]
- Holy harpoons!
The fortune did come true!
- 圣鱼叉！
运气果然实现了！
- Me cash register,
me money.
- 我的收银机，
我的钱。
- And that's why my depression
is award-winning.
- 这就是我抑郁的原因
是屡获殊荣的。
- Don't you see, Mr. Krabs?
- 你没看到吗，蟹老板？
The fortunes in those cookies
are real!
那些饼干里的财富
是真的！
Can't we share them
with everyone?
我们不能分享它们吗
和大家一起？
- [gasps, coughs]
- [喘气，咳嗽]
You know, you're right,
SpongeBob.
你知道，你是对的，
海绵宝宝。
We must share these
magical macaroons
我们必须分享这些
神奇的杏仁饼
with all the folks
in Bikini Bottom.
和所有的人
在比基尼底部。
You just leave it to me.
你就交给我吧。
- Oh, great!
- 哦，太棒了！
- [sighs]
Great.
- [叹气]
太棒了。
- This is how you hook 'em.
- 这就是你如何吸引他们。
Now remember,
the first one is free!
现在记住，
第一个是免费的！
[inhales, blows]
[吸气，吹气]
[crowd talks excitedly]
[众人兴奋议论]
- [chewing]
- [咀嚼]
"Something wonderful
is about to happen to you".
“一些美妙的事情
即将发生在你身上”。
[overlapping yipping]
[重叠的叫声]
[laughs]
I love puppies!
[笑]
我喜欢小狗！
Thanks, fortune cookie!
谢谢，幸运饼干！
- Oh.
"Eat your hat,
- 哦。
“吃掉你的帽子，
and you will
fall in love."
你会的
坠入爱河。”
Ha ha.
[chewing]
哈哈。
[咀嚼]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- [chewing]
Hmm?
- [咀嚼]
嗯？
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- [gulps]
Ah!
- [吞咽]
啊！
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
both: Thanks, fortune cookie.
两人：谢谢，幸运饼干。
- "You will soon
injure your legs"?
- “你很快就会
伤到你的腿”？
My legs!
我的腿！
I was looking for an excuse
to get out of jury duty!
我一直在寻找借口
逃避陪审义务！
[plays riff]
Thanks, fortune cookie!
[即兴演奏]
谢谢，幸运饼干！
- Those fortune cookies
are a hit!
- 那些幸运饼干
很受欢迎！
Whoa!
哇！
[all talking at once]
[大家同时说话]
- Fortune cookies
at the Krusty Krab, eh?
- 幸运饼干
在蟹堡王，是吧？
Well, Eugene,
I have a prediction too:
嗯，尤金，
我也有一个预测：
you are in for an epic fail
supreme with extra cheese.
你将会遭遇史诗般的失败
至高无上的额外奶酪。
[laughs]
- Sheldon!
[笑]
- 谢尔顿！
Where are you?
你在哪里？
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Barnacles, woman,
would it kill you
藤壶，女人，
它会杀了你吗
to leave me alone
for five minutes?
让我一个人呆着
五分钟？
- Sorry, your lordship,
- 对不起，陛下，
but the garbage isn't
going to take itself out.
但垃圾不是
会自己出去。
- Ugh!
[grunts]
- 呃！
[咕哝]
Riddle me this,
computer wife:
给我谜语，
电脑老婆：
What's hollow,
full of lies,
什么是空心的，
充满谎言，
and leaves a bad taste
in your mouth?
并留下不好的味道
在你嘴里？
- Our marriage?
- 我们的婚姻？
- No! Fortune cookies!
- 不！幸运饼干！
And Krabs is raking it
in right now
蟹老板正在掠夺它
现在
because all of his fortunes
are actually coming true.
因为他所有的财富
正在真正实现。
So...
- So, you've got an evil plan
所以...
- 所以，你有一个邪恶的计划
to get the Krabby Patty
secret formula
去获取蟹黄饼
秘方
and soon it will
be yours, all yours.
很快就会
是你的，全部都是你的。
[as Plankton]
Wah-hah-hah-hah-hah-hah-hah!
[作为浮游生物]
哇哈哈哈哈哈哈！
- Wow, I can't tell if
you're sarcastic or psychic.
- 哇，我不知道是否
你很讽刺或者通灵。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [chuckling]
- [轻笑]
Ooh, this'll be a good one.
哦，这将是一件好事。
"You...stink."
“你……太臭了。”
[laughs]
[笑]
[continues laughing]
[继续笑]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
*
Enjoy your new
fortune cookies, Krabs!
享受你的新
幸运饼干，蟹蟹！
- * La la
la-la-la-la-la-la *
- *啦啦
啦啦啦啦啦啦啦*
Time for a refill!
是时候补充一下了！
[crowd all talking excitedly]
[众人兴奋地议论]
- What is my future?
- 我的未来是什么？
- My tentacles
are gonna fall off
- 我的触手
会掉下来
if I don't get
a break soon, Mr. Krabs!
如果我没有得到
快休息一下吧，蟹老板！
- Look out, Mr. Squidward.
- 小心，章鱼哥先生。
I'll teach you how
to run a cash register.
我会教你如何
运行收银机。
[cracks knuckles]
[指关节嘎吱作响]
[nautical music speeds up]
[航海音乐加快]
Huh?
More cookies, SpongeBob!
啊？
更多饼干，海绵宝宝！
- Fortunes flying in,
Mr. Krabs!
- 财富飞来，
蟹老板！
- Let the wave
of misfortune begin!
- 让波浪
不幸的开始了！
- "You will get stomach cramps
from the Krusty Krab"?
- “你会胃痉挛
来自蟹堡王”？
- "An octopus with a big nose
just spit in your food"?
- “一只大鼻子的章鱼
只是吐在你的食物里”？
[melodramatic accent chords]
[戏剧性的重音和弦]
*
- "A yellow sponge will
serve you salmonella"?
- “黄色海绵会
为您服务沙门氏菌”？
- "You will live forever if
you eat at the Chum Bucket"?
- “如果你会永远活着
你在 Chum Bucket 吃饭吗？
- Let's eat at
the Chum Bucket!
- 我们去吃饭吧
密友桶！
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
[crowd talking excitedly]
[人群兴奋地议论]
- What did we ever do
to those fortune cookies
- 我们曾经做过什么
那些幸运饼干
to make them lie
about us like that?
让他们撒谎
关于我们这样吗？
- Well, the fortunes
in those cookies
- 好吧，命运
在那些饼干里
were always right before.
以前总是对的。
Here, Mr. Krabs--maybe this next
one'll change your luck.
在这里，蟹老板——也许是下一个
一个人会改变你的运气。
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
Hmm. "Unless you
give a tiny copepod
唔。 “除非你
给一个小小的桡足类动物
"the Krabby Patty
secret formula,
“蟹肉饼
秘密配方，
you will die"?
你会死”？
- Hello!
Did someone say "copepod"?
- 你好！
有人说“桡足类”吗？
[both screaming in panic]
[两人惊慌地尖叫]
Just wanted to borrow
a cup of grease, Eugene.
只是想借
一杯油脂，尤金。
I'll come back later!
Ciao!
我以后会回来的！
再见！
- J-just how true are these
cookie fortunes, SpongeBob?
- J-这些到底有多真实
饼干财富，海绵宝宝？
- If the cookie says
it's true, then it's true!
- 如果cookie说
这是真的，那就是真的！
Horribly, terribly,
truthfully true!
可怕的是，可怕的是，
说实话！
[weeping loudly]
[大声哭泣]
- "You will die."
- “你会死的。”
[voice echoing]
Die...die...die...
[声音回响]
死……死……死……
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
- Oh, I'll miss you, Daddy!
[sobs]
- 噢，我会想念你的，爸爸！
[抽泣]
But I really can't
wait to spend
但我真的不能
等待花费
all your hard-earned
money on shoes!
你辛苦赚来的一切
钱买鞋！
- Me money!
- 我的钱！
- Mr. Krabs, no!
[wailing loudly]
- 蟹老板先生，不！
[大声哀嚎]
- [grunts]
- [wailing]
- [咕哝]
- [哀号]
[distantly]
Mr. Krabs?
[远处]
蟹老板？
Mr. Krabs, it's time.
蟹老板，时间到了。
- Aah-ha-ha!
- It's time to give up
- 啊哈哈哈！
- 是时候放弃了
the secret formula
to Plankton.
秘密公式
到浮游生物。
Because your life
is worth more
因为你的生活
更有价值
than some scrap
of paper in a bottle!
比一些废料
瓶子里有纸！
- You're right, me boy-o.
- 你是对的，我的孩子。
I got to face me fortune.
我必须面对我的命运。
- Don't crowd,
there's more chumbalaya
- 不要拥挤，
还有更多的 chumbalaya
where that came from,
unfortunately.
那是从哪里来的，
不幸的是。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[all chewing]
[全部咀嚼]
all: Ugh!
全体：呃！
- It's worth it
to live forever.
- 这是值得的
永远活下去。
- This scheme is working
perfectly.
- 这个计划正在发挥作用
完美。
And here comes
gullible Krabs now
来了
现在的蟹蟹很容易上当受骗
to hand-deliver
the secret formula.
亲手交付
秘密公式。
I promised
myself I wouldn't cry.
我答应过
我自己不会哭。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, this crowd
is impossible!
- 哦，这群人
是不可能的！
- Leave it to me,
Mr. Krabs!
- 交给我吧
蟹老板！
I'll make sure Plankton
gets his so you won't get yours.
我会确保浮游生物
得到他的，所以你不会得到你的。
Hot stuff comin' through!
热门内容来了！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[grunting noisily]
[大声咕哝]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- Don't worry, secret formula!
I'm coming, baby!
- 别担心，秘密配方！
我来了，宝贝！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Yow! Ow!
- 哟！噢！
- [struggling]
- [挣扎]
- [gasping excitedly]
- [兴奋地喘气]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Me wants that ba-ba!
我想要那个爸爸！
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- Here, Plankton. Mr. Krabs
wants you to have this.
- 在这里，浮游生物。蟹老板先生
希望你拥有这个。
- Heh, heh!
Finally!
- 嘿嘿！
最后！
[straining]
[紧张]
No!
不！
*
Whoa--[grunts]
哇——[咕哝]
Aah, aah!
啊啊啊！
[screams]
[尖叫声]
I have had enough!
我已经受够了！
Get out of my restaurant,
you mindless sheep!
滚出我的餐厅
你这没脑子的羊！
I wrote those fortunes!
这些算命都是我写的！
[all gasp]
They were fakes!
[全都喘气]
他们是假货！
Don't you get it?
Now all of you, out!
你不明白吗？
现在你们都出去！
[growls]
[咆哮]
- Let's go back to
the Krusty Krab!
- 让我们回到
蟹堡王！
all: Yeah!
- Yeah, back to the Krusty Krab!
全体：是啊！
- 是的，回到蟹堡王！
all: Yeah!
全体：是啊！
- Hmm hmm.
- [sighs]
- 嗯嗯。
- [叹气]
- I guess I didn't really
think that through.
- 我想我真的没有
想通了。
- I figured the funeral fortune
was phony, Flankton!
- 我计算了葬礼的财富
是假的，弗兰克顿！
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
What are you
gonna do about it, Eugene?
你是什么
尤金，你会怎么做？
- Nothing, Sheldon.
- 没什么，谢尔顿。
Here, have a fortune cookie.
来，吃一块幸运饼干。
- [grunts]
Huh.
- [咕哝]
呵呵。
"You will go on a long voyage
“你将踏上长途航行
where you will get
everything you deserve."
你会得到什么
一切都是你应得的。”
Hey!
嘿！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Uhh! Hey! Oof!
呃！嘿！钱币！
Mommy!
- [chomp]
妈妈！
- [咀嚼]
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
*